Guide to the Theodore Dorie Friend Collection, 1897-1990
Friend, Theodore Dorie Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Theodore Dorie Friend Collection, 1897-1990
6981
Friend, Theodore Dorie,
18.9
Printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection includes material from throughout the 20th century relating to various political and regional events and trends during this time period in Southeast Asia.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Theodore Dorie Friend, is a graduate of Williams College (BA 1953) and Yale University (Ph.D. 1958). Dr. Friend is the President Emeritus of Eisenhower Fellowships, a Senior Fellow at the Foreign Policy Research Institute, as well as a chair on the review panel for the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation. Dr. Friend also served as a Distinguished Visiting Professor of Southeast Asian Studies at John Hopkins University in 2004. Dr. Friend has written several books on Southeast Asia, including his latest publication, Indonesian Destinies, published by the Harvard University Press in 2003.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection includes material from throughout the 20th century relating to various political and regional events and trends during this time period in Southeast Asia. Subject matter includes Southeast Asian colonial administration, Philippine nationalism, Japanese military and foreign policies during World War II, various studies and papers in relation to the region, and material regarding President Manuel L. Quezon. Many of these documents describe or were drafted during times of ideological and conventional “wars” in Southeast Asia, domestic instabilities, and drastic regional changes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Friend, Theodore Dorie,; Quezon, Manuel Luis, 1878-1944
Subjects:
Presidents -- Philippines; World War II
Places:
Philippines -- World War, 1939-1945; Philippines -- Japanese Occupation, 1942-1945; Philippines -- History; Philippines -- Politics and government; Indonesia -- History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Yale Dissertation and Between Two Empires, Research Materials
Box 1
Series II. The Philippine Polity: A Japanese View
Boxes
Series III. The Blue Eyed Enemy
Boxes
Series IV. Research Materials, Philippines and Indonesia
Boxes
Series V. Other Publications and papers
Boxes
Series VI. Travel documents, Seminars and Lectures in Philippines, China
Boxes
Series VII. Conferences and Papers
Boxes
Series VIII. The President Manuel L. Quezon Collection
Boxes
Series IX. Personal documents: Swarthmore College, applications, Wilson Fellowship
Boxes
Series X. Microforms, Disks, transparencies
Boxes
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Yale Dissertation and Between Two Empires, Research Materials
  - Philippines Land Tenure Issue, 1958 – 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Reports and book excerpts
  - Analytical Writing and Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1957 Garcia election; Friend notes; Relationship between nationalism and communism; miscellaneous notes
  - Politics and Development, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Reports on Political Attitudes and Behavior; Community Development in Philippines
  - Tony Aquino- Recollections of Japanese occupation, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographical Aids to Documents, Philippines, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Felipe Buencamino, Jr., 1958 – 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Friend notes; Correspondence with Friend regarding President Osmena and sugar industry
  - J.A.E. Buiskool Thesis, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    “The Acquisition of Independence of the Philippines”
  - Philippines Arts and Culture (1 of 2), 1931, 1955 – 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Bibliography, publications and pamphlets
  - Philippines Arts and Culture (2 of 2), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Newspaper clippings
  - Ateneo de Manila University, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Course lecture notes, article and Friend writing
  - Dissertation, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Reader comments, summary, Department of the Army approval
  - Philippines Economic Development, 1959 – 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Publications, correspondence, conference papers
  - Family and Politics in Philippines, 1957 – 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Correspondence and materials relating to Quezon and Osmeña families
  - Philippines Standard of Living, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Greenberg dissertation
  - Business and Religious Attitudes toward Philippine Independence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    1961 Gurney Report on business and religious periodicals, 1933-1934
  - Senator Hawes 1931 Support for Independence, 1931, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Correspondence from Charles M. Hay Papers
  - Philippines Middle Class, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Publications by Henares family members of middle class position
  - Sugar Politics and Independence, Hester Critique, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Critiques and response on article for publication by Friend
  - Sugar Beet Production, 1954 – 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    International and United States statistics tables
  - Japanese Commercial Development, 1936, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Analyses translated from Japanese
  - Philippines Independence Question and Business, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Miguelo Ossorio- Correspondence and Ossorio extended response
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 1955 – 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Hardie Report, Phil-Am trade, American Bases, etc.
  - Quezon and Roxas Collections, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Library Aids and floorplan
  - Foreign Investment- Opposition by senator, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Newspaper Clipping
  - Research Expenses- Receipts, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hare-Hawes-Cutting Act, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Correspondence Quezon and Artemio Ricarte Vibora
  - Japanese WWII Report on Philippines, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Correspondence and notes
  - Alzina’s History of the Visayas, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Philippine Studies reprint
  - Peacetime Republic Chapter Review, 1958 – 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Review of manuscript by Courtney Whitney
  - Correspondence, J.A. Wolfson- Jose Yulo, 1958 – 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General Emilio Aguinaldo, 1897, 1933, 1943, 1955-1958, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Friend; Aguinaldo Plea for independence; Unpublished obituary written by Friend with photograph of Katipunan; Newspaper Obituaries; Map of Philippines senators
  - Congressional Voting on Philippines Independence, 1916, 1929-1934, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    1929-1934 breakdown; 1916 Jones Bill debate; summary tables
  - Hukbalahap (Philippine Communist Party), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Friend notes; Party documents
  - Dissertation, 1956 – 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Correspondence
  - 1957 National Elections, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Newspaper articles and ads on elections and involvement of the church, roster of the 4th Congress
  - Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1933, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Checklist of archival materials on the Philippines, translation of 1933 (?) Japanese study of the Philippines independence question
  - Graphic and Tabular Materials, 1930-1940s (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Photographs especially concerning Quezon and Laurel, miscellaneous statistical materials, MacArthur report on Philippines national defense, political cartoons
  - Philippines Retail Trade Nationalization, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Hartendrop deportation question, Journal of American Chamber of Commerce of the Philippines
  - “Peacetime Rebublic”, Hester Critique, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Critiques and response on chapter “Peacetime Republic”
  - Philippines Decolonization, Russian View, 1958 – 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Translations of 1957-1958 analyses by G.I. Levinson on workers movement and independence question, Friend notes
  - MacArthur and Philippines National Defense, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Notes and list of materials
  - Puerto Rico, Economic and Political Development, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Questions and response by Governor Luis Muñoz Marin
  - Correspondence, Michael Onorato, 1960 – 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Onorato critique of Friend doctoral thesis and outline of Onorato manuscript
  - President Sergio Osmeña, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Correspondence and notes regarding Philippine independence and politics
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Independence and WWII- Hukbalahaps trial, Gen. MacArthur, 10th Anniversary of independence
  - Historiography of Spanish Rule, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Economy, military bases, land
  - Manuel L. Quezon Collection, 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Business, speech proposing collection
  - Manuel L. Quezon Personal Finances, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Filipino Central Committee Letter to US President, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Opposition to US annexation
  - Stonehill Case, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Notes, research, newspaper articles
  - Philippines Sugar Industry, 1920’s, 1953, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Taipei Libraries, Philippines Research Materials, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Lists and correspondence
  - Agrarian Radicalism and Luis Taruc, 1958 – 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Interviews, writings, and notes
  - Herbert Hoover Independence Veto, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Correspondence with Hoover, research materials
  - Senatorial Voting on Philippines Independence, 1920s-1930s, 1958 – 1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Philippine Independence Movement, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    trans. Notes- Notes on Taiwan sources
  - Notecards "Between Two Empires", 1958 – 1965 (Box 20)
    Disposition of Notes written by Friend (item number 3) to describe contents of boxes 21 through 23; Notecards for book chapters Prologue through 11
  - Notecards "Between Two Empires", 1958 – 1965 (Box 21)
    Notecards for book chapters 12 through 15, epilogue, sources, photographs, projects, and agenda of corrections
  - Notecards "Between Two Empires", 1958 – 1965 (Box 22)
    Notecards for agenda of corrections, MacArthur gallery notes, topical file for names and subjects arranged alphabetically
  - Miscellaneous Notes Between Two Empires and Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 23)
- Series II: The Philippine Polity: A Japanese View
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1941 (1 of 8), 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1942-1944 (2 of 8), 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1942-1944 (3 of 8), 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1941-1944 (4 of 8), 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1939 (5 of 8), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Speech, “New Deal for the Laboring Classes in the Philippines”
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1931 (6 of 8), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Speech
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1941 (7 of 8), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Dr. Palomares’ case
  - President Manuel L. Quezon Records, 1941 (8 of 8), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Recollections of Quezon by Taruc
  - President Jose P. Laurel Records, 1944 (1 of 5), 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Speeches
  - President Jose P. Laurel Records, 1943 (2 of 5), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Preparatory committee on Philippine independence
  - President Jose P. Laurel Records (3 of 5), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Salvador H. Laurel speech, correspondence and speeches from Laurel law office
  - President Jose P. Laurel Records (4 of 5), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Wartime activities and post war defense, 1944
  - President Jose P. Laurel Records (5 of 5), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Memorandum on Puppet Government. 1940s
  - Osmena, Sergio (1 of 4), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Government in exile, finances
  - Osmena, Sergio (2 of 4), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    The New Philippine Ideology, 1945
  - Osmena, Sergio (3 of 4), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Liberation and Independence of Philippines, 1945
  - Osmena, Sergio (4 of 4), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    End of World War II, Reconstruction, 1945
  - Roxas, Manuel, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Deposition, Wartime Collaboration, Hukbalahaps
  - Penafrancia Conferences, 1942, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The American Chamber of Commerce Journal, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    1943 Pact with Japan
  - KATHA Articles on Philippines, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    “What are Filipinos Like?” and “The Filipino Woman”
  - Mararo Concept of “Maratabat”, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Correspondence and AAS Presentation
  - Japanese Occupation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    AAS Annual Conference paper and notes
  - General Basilco J. Valdes, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Speech, miscellaneous
  - Subhash Chandra Bose (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Novel by Hugh Toye
  - Subhas Chandra Bose (2 of 2), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Research and Conversations with Sisir Bose
  - Wang Ching-Wei, Republic of China, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Philippines Nationalist Party, Presidential Convention, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Bayanihan- Entertainment, Philippines media resources, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Archival Aids, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Archival Aids- Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs and US National Archives
  - Philippines Relations under Sato and Marcos, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Newspapers, Manila (1 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Newspapers, Manila (2 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Conference Papers, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Association for Asian Studies and International Conference on Asian History
  - Takeuchi, Mikio (1 of 10), 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Interviews, Japanese Army, Notes
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(2 of 10), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Japan Research Trip, Correspondence
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(3 of 10), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Notes of conversations, Sept.-Nov. 1958, 2nd Series
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(4 of 10), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Gaimusho Documents, Translations, Philippines Independence
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(5 of 10), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Rikugunsho Documents, Checklist
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(6 of 10), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Gaimusho Documents, “Philippine Independence Problem”
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(7 of 10), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Gaimusho Documents, Philippine Government
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(8 of 10), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Gaimusho Documents, Correspondence
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(9 of 10), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Gaimusho Documents, Assembly of Greater East-Asian Nations, 1943-1945
  - Takeuchi, Mikio(10 of 10), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Guggenheim, Research and business
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(1 of 7), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Manila Diary, account of occupation 1942-1943
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(2 of 7), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Manila Diary as edited Sept. 1967
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(3 of 7), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Manila Diary
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(4 of 7), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Report of the [Japanese] Research Comminssion on the Philippines, Vol. 4
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(5 of 7), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Royama Biographical Note, Representative Bibliography, and Appendices
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(6 of 7), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    The Philippine Polity, Translation Method
  - Takeuchi, Tatsuji(7 of 7), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    The Philippine Polity, Editorial Notes, Chapters 1-4
- Series III: The Blue Eyed Enemy
  - Research, Japanese Occupation of Philippines (1 of 4), 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, research materials, notes
  - Research, Japanese Occupation of Philippines (2 of 4), 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Correspondence, research materials, notes, maps
  - Research, Japanese Occupation of Philippines (3 of 4), 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Research, Japanese Occupation of Philippines (4 of 4), 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967-1971 (1 of 4), 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967-1971 (2 of 4), 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967-1971 (3 of 4), 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1967-1971 (4 of 4), 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Research Materials, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Corresponds with box 25
  - Expression and Repression under Dutch and American Rule, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Organization and Schedule, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Intro: North Atlantic Powers, SEA Peoples, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Multiple drafts
  - Prologue: Three Transformations, Four World Wars, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy: Title, Preface, Contents, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Organization and Schedule, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Research Materials, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    “Profile of Asian Minded Man”, income chart for 1931 SEA, “Social Change and the Individual”
  - Education, Philippines and Dutch East Indies compared, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Economic Dependence, Philippines and Dutch East Indies compared, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Political Participation, Comparison, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Politicial Expression and Repression, Dutch East Indies (1 of 2), 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Politicial Expression and Repression, Dutch East Indies (2 of 2), 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Research-related Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Wartime Philippines Photographs, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Photos for publication
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript for Publication, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (1 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (2 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (3 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (4 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (5 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (6 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (7 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (8 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters (9 of 9), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Manuscript Chapters, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (1 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (2 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (3 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (4 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (5 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Final Manuscript Chapters (6 of 6), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Book Manuscript 1 (1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Book Manuscript 1 (2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Book Manuscript 2 (1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Book Manuscript 2 (2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1973 Version, Cover through Chapter Two, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1973 Version, Chapters Three Through Five, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1973 Version, Chapters Six Through Nine, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1973 Version, Chapters Ten Through Thirteen, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1973 Version, Chapters Fourteen Through End, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Kodama correspondence on editing, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Questions Arising in Editing, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Bibliographic leads or ellipses, factual details needing specification and/or correction etc
  - Project Two: Editing 1983-1984, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography 1983, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Prologue and Preface, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Chapter One 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Two 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chapter Three 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Chapter Four 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Chapter Five 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Chapter Six 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Chapter Seven 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Chapter Eight 1983 without revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Chapter Nine 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Chapter Ten 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Chapter Eleven 1983 Revisions, The Blue Eyed Enemy, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1983 Revisions, Chapter 12, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1983 Revisions, Conclusions and Accumulated Notes, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1983 Revisions, The Sources, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy 1983 Revisions, Thoughts, publications and sources, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Graphic Materials and Contract, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Political and Military Photographs of Philippines and Indonesia 1930s-1940s, maps
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Photographic Research- Graphic materials, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence and Organization, Blue Eyed Enemy Publication (1 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence and Organization, Blue Eyed Enemy Publication (2 of 4), 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence and Organization, Blue Eyed Enemy Publication (3 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Organization, Blue Eyed Enemy Publication (4 of 4), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and Organization, Blue Eyed Enemy Publication, Readers’ responses, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Notes and Sections Manuscript, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revision for submission- Notes, preface, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions of Introduction, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 1, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 2, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 3, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 4 (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 4 (2 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 5, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 6, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 7, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 8 (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 8 (2 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 9 (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 9 (2 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 10 (1 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 10 (2 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 10 (3 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions chapter 11, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions conclusion (1 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions conclusion (2 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, Revisions conclusion (3 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - The Blue Eyed Enemy, The sources (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)